<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>webassembly on Sébastien Deleuze</title><link>https://seb.deleuze.fr/tags/webassembly/</link><description>Recent content in webassembly on Sébastien Deleuze</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seb.deleuze.fr/tags/webassembly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>WebAssembly impact on programming languages</title><link>https://seb.deleuze.fr/webassembly-impact-on-programming-languages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seb.deleuze.fr/webassembly-impact-on-programming-languages/</guid><description>First some context: WebAssembly Component Model (WIT) is maturing in order to standardize reusable components. When ready, WIT components will likely be published in a repository (like npm or Maven Central but for Wasm) in a polyglot fashion targeting any language that supports Wasm.
Wasi (the Posix of WebAssembly that allows to use it outside of the browser) is currently rebased on top of WIT (tentatively called Wasi Preview 2). With Wasi, Wasm could become a major way to deploy workloads on Edge and Cloud platforms.</description></item><item><title>WebAssembly Developper Experience presentation</title><link>https://seb.deleuze.fr/presentations/webassembly-developper-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seb.deleuze.fr/presentations/webassembly-developper-experience/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Bootiful podcast on GraalVM, AOT and WebAssembly</title><link>https://seb.deleuze.fr/podcasts/bootiful-podcast-graalvm-webassembly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seb.deleuze.fr/podcasts/bootiful-podcast-graalvm-webassembly/</guid><description/></item><item><title>My call for Kotlin as a major frontend language</title><link>https://seb.deleuze.fr/kotlin-major-frontend-language/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seb.deleuze.fr/kotlin-major-frontend-language/</guid><description>I try to push for quite a long time for first class support for WebAssembly in Kotlin because I really believe that frontend development is a domain where Kotlin can be as strong as in mobile, and because this is something that would also help to increase even more the adoption on server-side.
I truly appreciate all the work already done by Kotlin/JS and Kotlin/Native teams. The dead code elimination tool and the initial WebAssembly support in Kotlin/Native are important steps in the right direction.</description></item></channel></rss>